Excuse me, sir. Quick question for
you, man. Is this your Lamborghini?
Yeah.
And what do you do for a living out
in Los Angeles to be able to afford a Lamborghini?
I'm an AI.
AI. And are you a business owner?
Yeah.
How long have you been an entrepreneur for?
I started my first business 11 years ago.
What's been the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
$34 million.
And what happened that year that you
were able to make over $30 million?
Real estate boom. And ironically, what follows
a great increase calls a great decrease. And
it was just a few years
later that I lost over $100 million.
Have you ever been broke before?
Yeah, totally. For sure.
What industry did you pursue a career in?
Real estate.
And what do you do exactly?
I own a real estate brokerage.
What's been the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
A little over $8 million.
And how old were you when you became a millionaire?
23 years old.
I go all over the country just
asking business owners their advice to young entrepreneurs.
Is it cool if we ask you
a few questions outside of the car?
That's cool.
Are you self-made?
Yes.
How can somebody become a
real estate millionaire in today's world?
Los Angeles is the number six city in
the entire world with the most millionaires. And today,
I'm going to be going all over LA
asking multi-millionaires the most they've made in a
year.
And the most money they've lost in a year.
So with that being said, let's get this video
on the way.
All right, you guys, we're out in Beverly Hills
right now. My guy just put up in a Lamborghini
Aventador up the street. I'm going to go up and
see what he was able to do to be able
to afford this car out here in Los Angeles.
So with that being said, let's go see what
he has to say.
Excuse me, sir.
Quick question for you, man. Is this your Lamborghini?
Yeah.
And what do you do for a living out
in Los Angeles to be able to afford a Lamborghini?
I'm an AI.
AI. And are you a business owner?
Yeah.
How long have you been an entrepreneur for?
I started my first business 11 years ago.
Over these 11 years, what's been the most
amount of money that you've ever made in a
single year?
$40 million.
$40 million. As an eight-figure entrepreneur,
man, what's the best financial advice you'd
give to the younger generation today?
Don't ask for a salary. For the love
of God, don't ask for fucking salaries. That's such
a pussy move to make. You are ride or die
commission only. If you didn't make that money, you don't
deserve to eat, right?
Right.
If you make them a million dollars, you deserve
half that. That's the kind of deals you need
to be making. 50% commissions if I make
you over like 100 grand this month. How about
that? Can I do that? Can I make you
100 grand, please? Those are the kind of deals because
then it's no risk to them. Fuck a salary.
That's how you get stuck in a dead-end situation.
You have to do proper deals, commission only,
take the risk, ride or die. You don't deserve
to eat if you don't make money, and
that's what's going to incentivize your skill set
to make you the best that you can be.
Have you ever been broke before?
Bro, I used to eat Top Ramen, Pop
Tarts, breakfast, lunch, and dinner from having my
seventh software business flail into the ground.
I would eat it in the bathroom because
I didn't want my neighbors to see me
eating for breakfast, lunch, and dinner because that's
all I could afford. Bro, I've had life.
I got evicted twice, got my car repossessed once.
I had one day, I was sleeping on my
friend's floor. I had nothing but $20, a suitcase,
a laptop, and a moped, and on that day,
my scooter got stolen. No job. Bro, begging the
Chase bank attendant to take $40 because I
was negative $80 in my bank account, and I
was trying to tell him to wipe it even
so I'd stop getting these fees. It's the fucking
real deal. Dude, that's life.
Man, that's life.
For somebody who may be at rock bottom
right now, what is an actionable step that they
can really take? What's your best
self-improvement advice to somebody out there?
I read like 200 books on sales and
business and the subconscious mind. Last book I ever
read before my life took off, Conversations with
God by Neil Donald Walsh. The idea that
you control your reality a little bit
more than everyone else thinks you do. Manifesting,
it's the real deal, and that book was the
last thing I read before I met my mentors
that took it all off.
What's the most amount of money
that you've lost in a single year?
95% of all the money that
I made when I sold my skincare.
Bram, went out the window.
What keeps people broke in today's world?
You look at society as a whole.
Friends.
Bro, friends easy, dog. I heard that quote,
you are the average of your five closest friends.
I'm like, yeah, I'm an entrepreneur. I
look at my friends, all broke entrepreneurs. I'm
like the sixth broke entrepreneur hanging out
in the crew of broke entrepreneurs. Nothing
against my friends, but I wanted to make $1,000
a day on the internet. Who am I hanging out
with making $1,000 a day? Nobody, right? So I
went on a side quest. I started a mastermind
group. I'm going to put together five guys who
are making $1,000 a day, do a native advertising,
affiliate marketing, different industries.
So we're not competing. And through that
group, my skillset started to explode. And
through that group is actually how I met
my mentors that kicked it all off for me.
That shit was great, bro. That shit was
phenomenal, bro. Seriously, Peter, thank you so much.
This video just got off to a crazy start,
you guys. My guy in the Lamborghini made $40
million this last year because he built
an artificial intelligence company and he just
dropped some amazing advice. I love how he
said, do not take a salary no matter what
you do. It's all about commission. Take
that commission, start that business, and that's
how you can make it happen. And that's
how he's one of the most successful entrepreneurs
in Los Angeles.
Great first interview of the day. Let's go
get this next one. Excuse me, sir. Question
for you. Have you ever been broke before?
Yeah, totally.
Yeah?
For sure.
What industry did you pursue a career in?
Real estate.
And what do you do exactly?
Build houses.
You build homes?
Yeah.
How long have you been a business owner for?
23 years.
Over those 23 years, what's the greatest
lesson you learned about entrepreneurship you'd pass
on to someone about to start their first business?
Take risks.
Take risks. What's the importance of
taking risks at an early age?
Huh?
What's the importance of taking risks at an early age?
Nothing ventured, nothing gained.
I love that. Two last ones for you.
What's the best financial advice that you've received
throughout your career?
Doubles and singles only.
What does that mean? Break that down?
Doubles and singles.
Break that down.
Don't go for the home run. Go for
the double, go for the single. You're good.
Well, I guess over those 23 years, in terms
of revenue, what was the most amount of money
that your business made?
I don't know. A lot.
A lot? Would you say like in eight figures?
For sure.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Eight? Eight figures?
In a year?
Yeah.
No.
Okay, seven figures though.
For sure.
Why was real estate your vehicle?
I was a real estate lawyer for 20 years.
So you were a lawyer?
Yeah.
Are you self-made?
Yeah?
Yeah.
So you don't come from money?
No.
For somebody who's maybe in that position,
let's say that they're broke, they're starting
out coming out of school, what's an actionable
step they can take to get really serious about
becoming financially free?
Work hard and do well in your school.
But you can work hard and work at McDonald's.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
Any job is a good job.
What did you see in the
business world that made you stand out?
Everyone you do business with, you can learn something from.
Just try to learn something from everybody.
Yeah.
That's it.
All right?
I love that.
Thank you so much for your time, sir.
I really appreciate it.
What's your name?
Michael Shore.
Great to meet you, sir.
Have a great day.
Hey, all I got to say,
man, crazy snag out here, man.
We stopped him to do the interview.
You got to be relentless.
Ask good questions and you'll
get some answers from them, man.
Great interview out in LA, man.
Let's go get this next one.
All right, you guys.
My guy just put up in
a G-Wagon out here in Los Angeles.
We're going to go up and see what he was
able to do to be able to afford this G-Wagon.
Let's see what he has to say, man.
Excuse me, sir.
Quick question for you, man.
Is this your G-Wagon?
It is.
And what do you do for living out in
Los Angeles to be able to afford a G-Wagon?
I own a real estate brokerage.
You own a real estate brokerage?
No.
How long have you been a business owner for?
Business owner for eight years.
Real estate industry, 19.
19 years.
And over these 19 years, what's been the most
amount of money that you've ever made in a
single year?
A little over $8 million.
$8 million.
And how old were you when you became a millionaire?
23 years old.
I go all over the country just
asking business owners their advice to young entrepreneurs.
Is it cool if we ask you
a few questions outside of the car?
That's cool.
Awesome.
Then let's run it.
How can somebody own a G-Wagon in today's world?
Buy a property, rent it
out, then buy a second one.
Buy a house every year for four years.
By the fifth year, between the passive income,
take that money and put it into a monthly
payment of your G-Wagon.
And that's the game right there.
And that's what it is.
That's all it is.
That way you don't have to ever worry
about making a payment because your tenants do it.
Is that your secret to creating wealth in real estate?
Yeah.
Buy assets, hold assets, take the
income, build businesses, rinse and repeat.
As a business owner that's been able to
scale this big business, how important was it for
you learning how to delegate?
Because a lot of entrepreneurs, they want
to be that solopreneur, wear all the hats
themselves.
How important was it for
you bringing in the right people?
Going back to my earlier days, the exposure
they had with that entrepreneur that I went
to work for at 15, he did absolutely nothing.
I mean, if anything, he went
in there and he had conversations.
With his leadership team for
like 30 minutes to an hour.
And then he just enjoyed his day every single day.
Every single facet of everything within the organization
from A to Z was managed by another
human.
That's how you scale.
But you have to have it with the right people.
So the ability of hiring the right
people, onboarding the right people and keeping the
right people, that's the trade that you learn over time.
You're not going to learn that in school.
You might have to have some errors
and some loss of money, maybe some failures.
But that's what separates the people that make
it really big and the people that don't
that have some failure at the beginning.
And then they end up...
Just saying, it's not worth it.
I'm just going to do it myself.
Be a contractor.
Do the A to Z.
Open up the store.
Lock it up.
Cashier.
Make the coffee.
What was the number one book that changed your life?
There's a book by John D.
Rockefeller.
That's 38 letters to his son.
Why was John D.
Rockefeller so successful?
Because he was ruthless.
He was relentless.
If he was in a territory where there was
competitors, he would bleed them to death and he
would take them on board.
And if there was talented people in those
companies, he would hire and bring them on
board.
I mean, he monopolized his industry.
Something that's never been done
since then for obvious reasons.
Good reasons too.
What was the best financial?
Decision that you made throughout your career?
Buying a house.
I bought my first house at 19.
Since then I bought over
125, maybe close to 130 now.
How many properties do you own?
Today I own 26, 34 doors.
Incredible man.
In Los Angeles.
That is phenomenal, man.
Thank you so much for your
time and I appreciate you, man.
That was great.
Seriously.
All right, you guys.
So Eric just went crazy coming out of the
G wagon, but I have a very special surprise
for you guys right now.
We are at SoFi Stadium, the home to
the Los Angeles Rams and the Los Angeles Chargers
to interview David Meltzer, who is
a nine figure Los Angeles entrepreneur.
He is a...
He's invited us out to the
stadium to ask him some questions.
So with that being said, let's go get some
game from David and see what he has to say.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
Sports and entertainment.
And how long have you been in the business for?
35 years.
Over these last 35 years, what has been
the most amount of money that you've ever made
in a single year?
$34 million.
And what happened that year that you
were able to make over $30 million?
Real estate boom.
Yeah.
Real estate doubled.
And so all the real estate
that I had doubled in one year.
And ironically,
what follows a great increase calls a great decrease.
And it was just a few years
later that I lost over $100 million.
That's incredible.
What happened that year that you lost $100 million?
I learned that lesson, asked for help.
So I had a huge line
of credit at my private bank.
And in 2008, when I needed about $5 million,
even though I had a $40 million line of credit,
very quickly I realized when
I walked in and they said,
hey, nobody told you you have
a cap of $1 million line.
You got to reapply.
And in 2008, it was much more difficult.
I had to call to get
the lines of credit that were necessary.
And so when you have a huge economy,
an economy that can afford you
$30 some million in one year,
things move very fast.
And that's how I ended up losing everything.
If I just would have asked for
help from someone that actually knew financing,
knew banking, I could have really done well.
And I'd be sitting in an entirely different situation.
Now, I lost everything and made it back,
but I would have had about 10 times as
much if I just would have asked for help.
What's the number one mistake you see business owners make?
They don't know the golden rule of business,
which is,
stay in business.
See, the first rule that I have every day,
and I have the biggest waiting
room in the history of waiting rooms,
about 65,000 seats in my waiting room.
So things are going well.
But the reason they're going well
is because I have one rule.
Make sure I'm in business tomorrow.
And so once I started following that directive,
I'll never go out of business because
I'm not going to sleep until I guarantee
I'm in business tomorrow.
Everything else is gravy because I know
if I stay in business sooner or later,
if you learn to love what
you don't love or don't like,
other people don't love or like,
if you learn to love what
if you do it consistently and persistently every day,
life and business will tell you all its cheat codes.
It'll tell you all its secrets.
And when you know the secrets, this game is easy,
but you got to be in the game.
So you got to guarantee that you're playing the game,
which is why the number one rule in
business is to make sure every day you
stay in business.
Among yourself and the most highly
successful people that you study and know,
what is that one trait
that they all have in common?
Consistency.
It's a simple skill,
but the simple things to do
are unfortunately simple not to do.
You see,
people that,
that do things every day allow for the physics,
metaphysics and quantum physics to work in their favor.
If you do something every single day,
it accelerates,
it aggregates and it creates exponentiality of outcomes.
Consistency is the number one habit.
It's actually the habit machine of habits,
but you have to be consistent.
In fact,
two minutes a day is
worth two hours on a Saturday.
Break that down.
Why is that?
Energy is behavior and so is money,
for example.
So even as far back as Einstein,
when he explained the rule of 72 compounding of interest,
it's really,
really compounding of energy.
See, energy has three characteristics.
It aggregates,
it attracts like energy,
it accelerates so things happen faster,
but most importantly,
it creates compound interest.
It creates exponentiality.
So people that are not utilizing that consistency,
they get one plus one plus one every day.
Those people that understand the physics,
quantum physics and metaphysics get one plus
two plus four plus eight plus 16
each day.
I love it.
Phenomenal.
So my guy,
David Meltzer lost over $100 million
in a single year and he made it
all back and he just gave a phenomenal interview.
Guys at SoFi Stadium,
that is the most expensive stadium in the entire world.
But guys, that's a wrap on today's video.
So be sure to leave a like and
subscribe for amazing content coming soon and click
in the description below because
we launched the Hard Knocks newsletter,
but we're going to be sending out weekly updates,
insights and lessons from the
world's top entrepreneurs and business owners.
So with that being said, we'll
see you guys in the next video.
Click here to watch our
full video going all over Miami,
asking multimillionaires how they became wealthy
and how you can start your path
to becoming financially free in 2024.
We'll see you in the next video.